（トンの食べる音）
（アナウンス）間もなく
３番線に 電車が参ります
Train arriving at platform three.
白線の内側に下がって
お待ちください
Please wait behind the line.
（電車の走行音）
（トンの飲み込む音）
（トン）今日は一日
忙しくなるな
Today will be a very busy day.
RAGE
♪～
～♪
（烈子(れつこ)）トン部長の件は
鷲美(わしみ)さんが話をつけてくれたけど…
It was nice of Ms. Washimi
to talk to the president on my behalf
あのトン部長のことだからな…
but given what Director Ton is like...
I'm a little... scared.
何だか ちょっと怖いな
（走る足音）
（フェネ子(こ)）ハア ハア ハア
フェネ子 どうかしたの？
Fenneko, what's up?
（フェネ子）経理部が…
大変なことになってる
There's chaos...
in Accounting!
（烈子）ん？
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
（一同のおびえ声）
皆さん
おはようございます！
Good morning, everyone!
ニヒッ
（一同）わあああ！
（トン）おはようございます！
今日も一日 頑張りましょう！
Good morning!
Let's do our best today!
カバ恵(え)さん
おはようございます！
Mrs. Kabae, good morning!
（カバ恵）うわ～！
うっ う…
（ハイ田(だ)）カバ恵さんもやられたぞ
気を付けろ～！
Mrs. Kabae is down too!
Be careful!
Director Ton! I beg you! Please stop!
（小宮(こみや)）トン部長！
お願いですから おやめください
加湿器の水は
私(わたくし)が替えますから～！
I'll change the water
in the humidifier!
（トン）何を言うんだ 小宮君
Don't be absurd, Komiya!
自分のことは自分でやらないと
It's my problem, I'll deal with it.
No way!
ひぎゃあああああ！
（烈子）この破壊力… 想定外！
I never imagined...
such mass devastation.
TEA ROOM
This is awkward
but I suppose he's trying to repent.
（烈子）ちょっと不器用だけど
トン部長なりに―
一応 反省してくれた
ってことなんだろうな
あ 烈子 いた
Can I join you?
（烈子）どうしたの？
What is going on?
I can't take Director Ton's cheerful mood.
I need to hide.
トン部長の笑顔に
耐え切れなくなって逃げてきた
あの場にいると 体と精神に
変調をきたすよな
Our minds and bodies
can't function properly in there.
あら みんなも逃げてきたの？
Oh! You also ran away?
何か調子 狂っちゃうよね～！
（ハイ田）ちょっと 何 何 何…
-I am going crazy!
-What, what?
（フェネ子）
カバ恵さん 狭い 狭い 狭い
We're cramped here!
（坪根(つぼね)）べ… 別に
逃げてきたわけじゃないのよ
I'm not coming to hide!
誰でもいいから
この つくだ煮の蓋 開けてくれる？
I just need someone
to open the jar for me.
（大上(おおかみ)）あ 俺やるっす
（小宮）トン部長～！
-I'll do it!
-Director Ton!
This is the evacuation area
for Accounting.
経理部の避難所になってきてるな
（烈子）すいませーん 通りまーす
（フェネ子たちのうめき声）
Excuse me!
Coming through!
あ 烈子 まさか それ
トン部長に持ってくのか？
Retsuko, don't tell me you're bringing
this cup of tea to Director Ton?
（烈子）
うん 一応 いれなきゃかなって
I feel like I should.
（ハイ田）また あの危険区域に
戻るつもりかよ？
Seriously? You're returning
to the danger zone?
（フェネ子）気を付けて
Be careful!
まともに目を合わせちゃ駄目よ
（烈子）大丈夫です
Don't make eye contact!
I'll be fine.
（そろばんをはじく音）
（烈子）トン部長 お茶をどうぞ
Director Ton. Here's your tea.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
（烈子）う…
失礼します
Excuse me.
（トン）うおおお～
Don't tell me... Is she the one
who ratted me out to the president?
まさか こいつが 社長に
チクりやがったのか？
KARAOKE
（鷲美）とりあえず―
By the looks of it, it's a success.
作戦は
うまくいったってことかしらね
ありがとうございます
鷲美さんのおかげです
Thank you very much, Ms. Washimi!
It's all thanks to you!
（ゴリ）でも 安心するのは
まだ早いんじゃない？
But it's too early to celebrate, isn't it?
え？
（鷲美）烈子と トン部長の間には
まだ高い壁があるわ
There's still a high wall
between you and Director Ton.
社長に くぎ刺されて
おとなしくしてるだけで―
He's being nice because
he received a warning.
Nothing has changed
in your relationship.
あなたたちの関係性は
何も変わってないでしょ？
ああ…
You two need a chance
to find common ground.
（鷲美）お互いの理解を
深める機会が必要ね
何か ないの？
（烈子）え…
How about...
（鷲美）飲み会とか
a drinking party?
ああ～
でも 私 苦手なんですよね
会社の飲み会
I don't really like office parties.
（鷲美）
最近 こういう子 多いわよね
A lot of girls are like that lately.
分かる
うちの若い子も こんな感じ
Yes! The young people I know
are the same!
ねえ 烈子 古くさいと
思うかもしれないけど―
Hey, Retsuko. You might think
it's old-fashioned, but...
酒の席で親睦を深めるって
今も昔も絶対有効よ
developing relationships over drinks
is still very effective.
（鷲美）上手に賢く利用しなさい
Be smart and take the opportunity.
（烈子）う…
Man, I thought I was going to die!
（ハイ田）いや～ そんときは
マジ 死ぬかと思ったよ～
-Mr. Haida!
-What?
（大上）ハイ田先輩！
あ？
（大上）月末の飲み会 出ます？
Are you coming to
end-of-the-month office drinks?
あ～ めんどくせえな
どうすっかな～
Ah, what a pain. What should I do?
会費払って 上司の自慢話
聞かされるとか うぜえしな
We pay money to listen to the bosses
singing their own praises.
（大上）ね
勘弁してほしいっすよね
I wish they'd give us a break.
俺 不参加でいいや
Put me down as a "no".
That's a "no" from Mr. Haida.
How about you, Ms. Retsuko?
（大上）ハイ田先輩 不参加っと
烈子先輩は？
あ 参加で
A "yes" from me.
（大上）参加… っと
"Yes" it is.
烈子… 出んの？
Retsuko, are you going?
（烈子）うん
Yes.
（ハイ田）
やっぱ 俺 参加にしといて
I changed my mind.
（大上）えっ
What? Didn't you just say
office parties are a pain?
でも さっき“めんどくさい”って
言ったじゃないすか
うっせえな！
気が変わったんだよ
Shut up! I changed my mind, okay?!
Just put me down as a "yes"!
いいから 参加にしとけよ！
面白そうだから 私も参加
Should be fun. I'm in too.
IZAKAYA
HOT POT
（大上）
え？ 今 どの辺っすか？
Where are you now?
は？ これから 電車乗るとこ？
マジすか
What? Just getting on the train?
But we've started
the first round of drinks already!
もう みんな 上で
乾杯しちゃいましたよ
はい　はーい
Okay.
Okay, understood.
はい 分かりました
Just make your way over here.
じゃ 気を付けて来てくださーい
（ハイ田）チッ ああ～ クソ～
Shit...
This party was supposed
to be my chance...
やっと こぎ着けた
飲み会だってのに
Cheers!
（烈子たち）かんぱーい！
（一同の騒ぎ声）
そういえば ハイ田君は？
（フェネ子）遅れるってさ
-Where is Haida?
-He's running late.
（ハイ田の荒い息）
（ハイ田）ハッ ハッ？
（ハイ田）あいつ！ 何ちゃっかり
烈子の隣 座ってんだよ
He has some nerve sitting next to Retsuko!
（カバ恵･坪根）ハイ田く～ん！
Haida!
Over here!
こっち こっち～！
はああ～
Director Ton, you really
know how to drink!
（小宮）トン部長
いい飲みっぷりでございますね～
（トン）ハッハハハハハ
今日は いい気分だ
ハハハハハ
I'm in a good mood today.
（烈子）ゴリ部長 鷲美さん
見守っててください
Director Gori, Ms. Washimi,
please watch over me.
ブハ～！
（烈子）トン部長 お疲れさまです
Director Ton,
thank you for your hard work.
Oh, short...
おお～ 腰掛… あああ…
烈子君！
（烈子）グラス 空いてますよ
Retsuko!
Let me refill your glass.
Label facing up, you see!
ラベルは上に でしたよね
記憶力は
悪くねえようだな
So you remember!
ハハッ
（烈子）フフッ
（２人の笑い声）
だが つぎ方がなってねえな
貸してみろ
You still aren't pouring it the right way.
Give me the bottle.
おう
（烈子）あ…
お前 仕事は どうするんだ？
続けるのか 辞めるのか
What are your plans about the job?
Are you staying? Or quitting?
つ… 続けるつもりです
I intend to continue.
そうか
I see.
I also learned my lesson.
俺も今回は さすがに懲りた
俺が若いころは そりゃ 厳しく
しごかれたもんだったが―
I was worked to the bone
when I was young.
今 同じつもりで指導すりゃ―
Now if you give orders the same way,
パワハラだ何だと
しっぺ返しを食らっちまう
they complain of "power harassment".
時代は変わった
Times have changed.
俺も もう年だな
I guess I'm growing old.
ハア… お前とも
いろいろあったが―
You've been through a lot as well.
I went a little too far...
少々やりすぎた
今まで―
I'm sorry about everything.
すまなかったな
トン部長…
Director Ton...
私こそ 至らないことばかりで
すみません
I am sorry for getting things wrong
all the time.
これからも ご指導 お願いします
There's so much I can learn from you!
それに―
And... don't be hard on yourself.
もう懲りたなんて
言わないでください
トン部長の熱心な ご指導あっての
経理部です
The department wouldn't be the same
without your strong leadership.
きっと トン部長の その気持ち―
And I'm sure that the president
社長も分かってくれますよ
knows how you feel.
（トン）社長？
The president?
何で 俺が 社長に
くぎ刺されたこと―
How do you know
that the president cautioned me?
知ってんだ？
（烈子）うぐっ
尻尾を出しやがったな
So the truth comes out.
この腰掛け女
You short-timer!
あああ あの…
違います 私は ただ…
No! I was just trying to deepen
my relationship with you.
トン部長との親睦を
深めようと思って
女ってやつは
ムシが好かねえ
I can't stand women...
いや お前のような女は
ムシが好かねえ！
Actually...
I can't stand women like you!
（烈子）
完全に裏目った～
That backfired completely!
（歓声）
（大上）あざっす あざーっす！
Thank you! Thank you!
というわけで 恒例の
カラオケ大会の時間帯となりました
And now, as usual, it's time
for the karaoke competition!
（歓声）
（大上）
幹事の大上 トップバッター
いかしていただきます！
Your party organizer Ookami
will sing first.
（ハウリング音）
（大上）あ… あ？
（ラップの音楽）
（一同の歓声）
（トンのラップ）
I was a new hire
Now I'm spitting hot fire
T-O-N's about to B-R-I-N-G
The hurt on you
Hey Retsuko! Why you working
If you hate your job so bad?
I dunno
It's just what you do
'Cause Retsuko's killin' time
Until she finds herself a man
I dunno
It's just what you do
Meek and mediocre
You never really stand out
Waitin' for your check
Like it's nothing but a hand-out
You're not the best
Or the worst I've seen
I called you out hard
And I'mma get away clean
（一同）
トン！ トン！ トン！ トン…
Ton! Ton!
アハハ… 烈子
ディスられてる ディスられてる
Retsuko! He just dissed you!
そして当たってる～
（烈子）うるさいな！
-And he isn't wrong!
-Shut up!
烈子！ 烈子！ 烈子！ 烈子～！
Retsuko! Retsuko!
言われっぱなしでいいのかよ
Are you going to let him say that?!
悔しくねえのかよ
Aren't you upset?
（社員たち）烈子！ 烈子！ 烈子…
Retsuko! Retsuko! Retsuko!
（ハイ田･フェネ子）烈子！ 烈子！
Retsuko! Retsuko!
（社員たち）烈子！ 烈子！
えーっと…
I...
ああ～
え～と
I...
フハハ…
返す言葉もねえってわけか
No comeback from you then?
俺は分かってたぜ
なぜなら お前はな…
What's the matter?
Does the cat have your tongue?
This is why you're on the bottom rung
（トンのラップ）
Chained to your computer
And you're sweating like a loser
While I crush you like a closer
Like a lyric bulldozer
Asleep on your feet
Come on, you're dead meat
No play, you're DOA
You got nothing to say
You're lazy
'Cause you go with the flow
And I can't figure out
If you're coming or going
Your sad little life
Got no rhythm or rhyme
I betcha that's why
You get drunk all the time
（笑い声）
（烈子）うう～ ううう…
（大上）
というわけで トン部長
入魂のラップでした～
There you have it.
Director Ton's epic rap!
（社員たち）トン！ トン！ トン…
（社員たちの歓声）
Ton! Ton! Ton!
（烈子）
ゴリ部長 鷲美さん…
Director Gori... Ms. Washimi...
Even though you were rooting for me...
せっかく応援してくれたのに
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
I couldn't do it after all.
私 やっぱり駄目でした
（烈子）この番号の曲で歌います
I'll sing the song for this number.
（大上）あ はい
Oh, sure.
ヘッ 童謡でも歌うのか？
ハハハハハ
Is it a nursery rhyme?
SEND
（デスメタルの音楽）
何だ こりゃ
What is this?
（ハイ田･フェネ子）烈子！ 烈子！
Retsuko! Retsuko!
（社員たち）烈子！ 烈子！
（鷲美･ゴリ）烈子！ 烈子！
Retsuko! Retsuko!
（社員たち）烈子！ 烈子！ 烈子…
（デス烈子の叫び声）
RAGE
うわああ～！
Why'd you go again?
Nobody wants to hear it!
Your beats are weak
And your rap sucks
Look at you standing there
Wanting a reply
Here it comes, pig!
Here's my battle cry!
You're a shitty boss!
I hate you so much!
ああああ… ううっ うう～…
ハハハハ… 覚えとけ
Remember this.
10年先 20年先―
Ten years... Twenty years from now...
お前も いつか
クソ上司になるんだって―
One day you'll become a shitty boss too...
ことを… な…
（いびき）
（店員）すいません
ラストオーダーになりまーす
Excuse me. Last orders?
♪～
～♪
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood